MASUD AFSAR

Senior Front-end Developer

📞 +98 (936) 311-6309 @ masud.afsar@gmail.com 🕜 skype:masud.afsar

SUMMARY

I am a senior front-end developer with over 6 years of experience in developing and optimizing web applications. I am interested in big teams with world-class products which affect the life of a huge amount of people. Currently, I am working on an online health platform with over 20 million users, called Snapp Doctor.

I have professional experience working with TypeScript, React.js, and Next.js and have worked in the e-commerce and health industries.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Front-end developer

06/2022 - Ongoing

Snapp! Doctor

Tehran, Iran

The most popular online health platform in Iran with over 20 million users with several services like consultation, medicine delivery, home care, lab, and so forth.

- Improved performance scores on Home, PLP, and PDP pages from 10~30 up to at least 75 scores on Lighthouse
- Reduced web app bundle size from 600 kb to 200 kb and it is serving over 1.2 million users
- Built a unified panel for pharmacy stores and support resulting in 50% less back and forth between stores and support.
- Refactored major features into cleaning more than 4000 lines of spaghetti code.
- Created a custom ticket service that reduced support ticket follow-up by 80%
- Collaborated with the UX/UI design teams to improve the website and applications, increasing conversion rates by 25%
- Daily maintenance of code, fixing issues, and implementing new features

www.snapp.doctor

Senior Front-end developer

04/2021 - 06/2022

Firooz Hygienic Group

Tehran, Iran

Firooz is exclusively engaged in designing and distributing baby hygienic products.

- Collaborated in developing an online marketplace to migrate from the legacy version
- Visualized sales and operation team information with charts and maps
- Dockerized and deployed the APIs and services on a cloud server with Docker Compose
- Responsible to train 2 people in the front-end basics and helping them develop further

www.firooz.com

Front-end developer

11/2020 - 07/2021

Digital First GmbH

Vienna, Austria

A start-up that helped entrepreneurs to develop their ideas.

- Improved performance scores from 25 up to at least 80 scores on Lighthouse
- Reduced web app bundle size from 740 kb to 270 kb
- Implemented a minimal audio player for listening to podcasts
- Designed a mini social media inspire of twitter with the support of gifs, emojis, and media
- Refactored a 7,000-line javascript code base to a clean typescript NextJS Project

Developer and Co-Founder

04/2015 - 12/2020

Ordibehesht Studio (Joyixir OÜ)

Qazvin, Iran

An indie mobile game studio

- Increased mobile game revenue over 6 times by developing an in-app purchase web API
- Implemented over 10 landing pages to introduce games
- Developed a matchmaker and game server over Socket with over 100 concurrent match
- Contributed to developing a word puzzle game with over 2 million active players in Iran
- published several hyper-casual mobile games on the Global market
- Responsible as a team lead in an online multi-player game it's call 4Wheelers which won the best multi-player games in the MENA region and was nominated for Global region
- https://apps.apple.com/us/developer/joyixir/id1534847102

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree, Computer **Software Engineering**

Azad University (IAU)

2008 - 2016

Qazvin, Iran

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript · TypeScript · Python

Libraries and Frameworks

React.js · Next.js · Zustand · Redux · Axios ·

React-Query · React Apollo · Emotion ·

Styled-components · Webpack · Vite.js ·

Turbo repo · Storybook.is · Cypress · Jest ·

React testing library

UI Frameworks

Material UI · TailwindCSS · Ant Design ·

Bootstrap

Others

Docker · Git · Figma · Gitlab CI/CD · Nginx ·

Apache · Restful APIs · GraphQL · Sass ·

SCSS · ESLint · Prettier · Husky

COURSES

Test-Driven Development with React By Irek Mirgaleev

React - The Complete Guide By Maximilian Schwarzmüller

LANGUAGE

English

Proficient

PASSIONS

open-source developing

Online Video Games